Register of the Gleb Struve Papers 1810-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, ARRANGED CHRONOLOGICALLY, 1916-1982 (Boxes 56-69)
  - Untitled memoranda (for Reuter's ?). Relates to nationalist policy of Stalin and strategic situation on Eastern Front, typescript, 1942 (Folder 23)
  - Review of C. M. Bowra, ed., Book of Russian Verse, The Listener, Dec. 30, 1943, printed copy (Folder 24)
  - Letters to the editor, 1945 (Folder 25)
  - "Pamiati Z. D. Shklovskoi", obituary, holograph draft, 1945 (?) (Folder 26)
  - Review of Janko Lavrin, Russian Poetry Reader, Modern Languages Review, 1945, printed copy (Folder 27)
  - Obituaries of Konstantin Balmont, Dmitry Merezhkovsky, Yury Tynyanov and Vladimir Burtsev, The Slavonic and East European Review, Jan. 1945 (Folder 28)
  - Review of Joseph Macleod, The New Soviet Theatre and Andre van Gyseghem, Theatre in Soviet Russia, The Slavonic and East European Review, Jan. 1945, printed (Folder 29)
  - "Slovo o Polku Igoreve -- An Eighteenth Century Fake?", review of Andre Mazon, Le Slovo d'Igor, The Slavonic and East European Review, Jan. 1946, printed copy (Folder 30)
  - Review of S. Konovalov and F. Friedeberg Seely, eds., Russian Prose Reader I. XIX Century Writers, The Slavonic and East European Review, Jan. 1946, printed copy (Folder 31)
  - "Blok and Gumilyov: a Double Anniverary", The Slavonic and East European Review, Nov. 1946, printed copy (Folder 32)
  - Review of Istorya russkoy literatury. Izdatel'stvo Akademii Nauk S.S.S.R., The Slavonic and East European Review, printed copy, Nov. 1946 (Folder 33)
  - Letters to the editor, 1947, printed copies (Folder 34)
  - "Tri sud'by: Blok, Gumilev, Sologub", Novyi Zhurnal, 1947, printed copy (Folder 35)
  - Review of M. Hofmann, Histoire de la litterature russe, Erasmus, March 1947 and also in The Slavonic and East European Review, April 1947, printed copies (Folder 36)
  - "Chetyre stikhotvoreniia", May 4, 1947, printed copy (Folder 37)
  - "Bibliografiia. Molodye parizhskie poety", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, June 21, 1947 (Folder 38)
  - "An Open Letter to Henry Wallace", letter to the editor of The New Leader, July 28, 1947, typescript draft (Folder 39)
  - "Pod znamenem svobody. O dvukh emigratsiiakh", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, July 28, 1947, printed copy (Folder 40)
  - "Mickiewicz in Russia", The Slavonic and East European Review, Nov. 1947, printed copy (Folder 41)
  - "Vystuplenie Ia. Tsekhanovskogo v kaliforniiskom universitete", Oct. 25, 1947, printed copy (Folder 42)
  - "Novoe o starom. Eshche o Iakinfe Bichurine", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Oct. 19, 1947, printed copy (Folder 43)
  - Book reviews, 1948-1949, printed copies (Folder 44)
  - Letters to the editor, 1948 (Folder 45)
  - "Artur Kestler o nashei epokhe i o tekushchem momente", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, 1948, printed copy (Folder 46)
  - "Sobytiia v Chekhoslovakii", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, March 7, 1948, printed copy (Folder 47)
  - "Ranniaia smert'. Pamiati L. V. Chernosvitova", Russkaia Mysl', April 16, 1948, printed copy (Folder 48)
  - "Ocherednoi Molotovskii obman", Russkaia Zhizn', May 15, 1948, printed copy (Folder 49)
  - "Novyi khod Moskvy", Russkaia Zhizn', May 22, 1948, printed copy (Folder 50)
  - "Prezident Triuman v Kaliforniiskom Universitete", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, June 16, 1948, printed copy (Folder 51)
  - "O starykh grekhakh i nashykh zadachakh", Russkaia Zhizn', Aug. 28, 1948, printed copy (Folder 52)
  - "O russkom Iazyke", A Pedagogical Journal in Russian, 1948, mimeograph tearsheets and Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Aug. 29, 1948 (Folder 53)
  - "Politicheskoe zaveshchanie Eduarda Benesha", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Oct. 2, 1948, printed copy (Folder 54)
  - Letters to the editor, 1949 (Folder 55)
  - "Introducing Peter Pavlenko", The New Leader, March 26, 1949, printed copy (Folder 56)
  - "Witch-Hunt: Russian Style. Soviets Purge Literary Scholarship", The New Leader, April 2, 1949, printed copy (Folder 57)
  - "A Belinsky Centenary Bibliography", The Slavonic and East European Review, May 1949, printed copy (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - "Novoe o starom", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, May 30-31, 1949, printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "Chelovechestvo v 1984 godu. Novyi roman o totalitarizme", Russkaia Mysl', June 24, 1949, printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Cherez 35 let. Novaia satira na totalitarizm", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, July 10, 1949, printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "O dvukh frontakh i o Lige bor'by za svobodu", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Aug. 1, 1949, printed copy (Folder 5)
  - "Novoe o starom", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Aug. 28, 1949, printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Eshche o predlogakh 'v' i 'na'", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Sept. 4, 1949, printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "John Paradise- Friend of Doctor Johnson, American Citizen and Russian 'Agent'", The Virginia Magazine of History and Biography, Oct. 1949, printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Istoriko-literaturnye zametki", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Oct. 9, 1949, printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Anti-Westernism in Recent Soviet Literature", The Yale Review, Dec. 1949, tearsheets (Folder 10)
  - Books Abroad, miscellaneous book reviews, 1950, printed copies (Folder 11)
  - Letters to the editor, 1950, printed copies (Folder 12)
  - "Sovetskii kritik liagaet Gershenzona", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Jan. 1, 1950, printed copy (Folder 13)
  - "Eshche o 'prosveshchennykh' ekspertakh po russkim delam", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Feb. 5, 1950, printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Kaliforniiskaia kliukva po-sovetski", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Feb. 19, 1950, printed copy (Folder 15)
  - Letter to the editor of Novaia Zaria. Relates to confusion between Otto Struve and Gleb Struve, March 1950, typescript draft (Folder 16)
  - "Kak sovetskie pisateli peredelyvaiut svoi veshchi", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, March 5, 1950, printed copy (Folder 17)
  - "La litterature sovietique et l'Occident", La documentation francaises. Articles et document., No. 1809, March 18, 1950, printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "Priznaniia Aleksandra Verta", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, April 23, 1950, printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "Lenin v tiurme i ssylke", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, May 25, 1950, printed copy (Folder 20)
  - "V zashchitu Josepha de Maistra", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, May 28, 1950, printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Rekord stalinopoklonstva", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Oct. 1, 1950, printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "Ob Il'fe i Petrove", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Nov. 27, 1950, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 23)
  - Books Abroad, miscellaneous book reviews, 1951, printed copies (Folder 24)
  - Russkii evropeets: materialy dlia biografii i kharakteristiki kniazia P. B. Kozlovskogo, 1951
    - Copyright claim, 1951 (Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous reviews, 1951-1952, handwritten, typescript and printed copies (Folder 26)
  - Soviet Russian Literature, 1951
    - Correspondence, see Russian Literature Under Lenin and Stalin
    - Reviews, 1951, typescript and printed copies (Folder 27)
  - "Amerika i Rossiia", Posev, Feb. 11, 1951, printed copy (Folder 28)
  - Books Abroad, miscellaneous book reviews, 1952, printed copies (Folder 29)
  - Letters to the editor, 1952, printed copies (Folder 30)
  - Miscellany. Includes short translations, short contributions to textbooks and journals, 1952, printed copies (Folder 31)
  - Anton Chekhov: Selected Short Stories, book reviews, 1952, typescript excerpts (Folder 32)
  - "Invisible Russia", review of V. Alekseev, Nevidimaia Rossiia, 1952(?), typescript draft (Folder 33)
  - "Den litteraere situasjonen i sovjetsamveldet", Vinduet, No. 2, 1952, printed copy (Folder 34)
  - "Dve knigi o sud'bakh Rossii", Novyi Zhurnal, No. XXIV, 1952, printed copy (Folder 35)
  - "Novye varianty shigalevshchiny", Novyi Zhurnal, XXX, 1952, printed copy (Folder 36)
  - "Sredi knig. O Kiustine i 'kiustinstvuiushchikh' inostrantsakh", Vozrozhdenie, March-April, 1952, printed copy (Folder 37)
  - Obituaries for V. N. Chelishchev, miscellaneous emigre journals, May 1952, printed copies (Folder 38)
  - "O Zhukovskom", Vozrozhdenie, May-June, 1952, printed copy (Folder 39)
  - Books Abroad and other book reviews, 1953, printed copies (Folder 40)
  - Letters to the editor, printed copies, 1953 (Folder 41)
  - "O sovetskoi poezii", Za Sv o bodu No. 8, 1953, printed copy. Also see scrapbook 1950-1959 (Folder 42)
  - "O dvukh antologiiakh russkoi poezii", Russkaia Mysl', Feb. 20, 1953, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 43)
  - "Pamiati V. A. Lazarevskogo", Russkaia Zhizn', Sept. 9, 1953, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1953 (Folder 44)
  - "Some Observations on Past Imperfective Gerunds in Russian", Word, Vol. 9, No. 4, 1953, reprint (Folder 45)
  - Book reviews, 1954, printed copies (Folder 46)
  - Letters to the editor, 1954, printed copies (Folder 47)
  - "The Double Life of Russian Literature", Books Abroad, Autumn 1954, typescript draft, notes and printed copy (Folder 48)
  - "O chistote russkogo iazyka i ob odnom voprose pravopisaniia", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, May 23, 1954, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 49)
  - "B. N. Volkov", Russkaia Mysl', July 9, 1954, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 50)
  - "Monologue Interieur: the Origins of the Formula and the First Statement of Its Possibilities", PMLA, Dec. 1954, printed copy (Folder 51)
  - Book reviews, 1955, printed copies (Folder 52)
  - Letters to the editor, 1955-1956, printed copies (Folder 53)
  - "The Second Congress of Soviet Writers", Problems of Communism, Vol. IV, No. 2, March-April 1955, printed copy (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - "Coexistence and Cultural Cooperation, An Open Letter to Professor Dmitry Blagoi of Moscow", typescript draft, 1955(?) (Folder 2)
  - "Eshche o s"ezde sovetskikh pisatelei", Russkaia Mysl', March 2, 1955, printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "Eshche o nedobrosovestnosti sovetskikh pisatelei", Russkaia Mysl', Aug. 3, 1955, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 4)
  - "O chekhovskom izdatel'stve voobshche i o 'litsakh' Zamiatina v chastnosti", Russkaia Mysl', printed copy, Aug. 12, 1955 (Folder 5)
  - "Slavonic Art and Letters", yearly review of literary activity in Russian field, covers period from 1956-1963, typescript and printed copies (Folder 6)
  - "Mickiewicz in Russian Translations and Criticism" and "Vladislav Khodasevich on 'Pan Tadeusz'", reprints of contributions to W. Lednicki, ed. Adam Mickiewiz in World Literature, 1956 (Folder 7)
  - Russkaia literatura v izgnanii: opyt istoricheskogo obzora, 1956, typescript draft, n.d.
    - Author's Preface (Folder 8)
    - Part I
      - Chapter I (Folder 9)
      - Chapter II-III (Folder 10)
      - Chapter IV (Folder 11)
      - Chapter V (Folder 12)
      - Chapter VI (Folder 13)
      - Chapter VII (Folder 14)
      - Chapter VIII (Folder 15)
    - Part II
      - Chapter I (Folder 16)
      - Chapter II (Folder 17)
      - Chapter III (Folder 18)
      - Chapter IV (Folder 19)
      - Chapter V (Folder 20)
      - Postscript (Folder 21)
      - List of emigre authors (Folder 22)
      - Reviews, typescript and printed copies, 1956-1985 (Folder 23)
    - Draft of translation by David Pike entitled "Russian Literature in Exile", typescript, n.d.
      - Part I
        - Chapter I-III (Folder 24)
        - Chapter IV (Box 62, Folder 1)
        - Chapter V (Folder 2)
        - Chapter VI (Folder 3)
        - Chapter VII-VIII (Folder 4)
      - Part II
        - Chapter I (Folder 5)
        - Chapter II (Folder 6)
        - Chapter III (Folder 7)
        - Chapter IV (Folder 8)
        - Chapter V and Notes (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with emigre authors about biographical data, 1955-1956 (Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous handwritten notes, n.d. (Folder 11-12)
    - Draft for projected history of emigre literature, "Russkaia literatura za rubezhom", to be edited by Gleb Struve and V. Kostetskii, typescript, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - "Pro Domo Mea", letter to the editor of Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Oct. 7, 1956, printed copy (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - "Comparative Literature in the Soviet Union: Two Postscripts", Yearbook of Comparative and General Literature, No. 6, 1957 (Folder 2)
  - Geschichte der Sowjetliteratur, Isar Verlag, Munchen, 1957
    - Correspondence between Gleb Struve and Gunter Schafer, 1956-1957 (Folder 3)
    - Typescript drafts, n.d.
      - Chapter VIII (Folder 4)
      - Chapter XIV (Folder 5)
    - Reviews. Clippings from German periodical press, 1958-1959 (Folder 6)
    - Catalogue, Isar Verlag, 1957/1958 (Folder 7)
  - "The Impact of the Revolution on the Russian Language", Kentucky Foreign Language Quarterly, 1957, typescript copy (Folder 8)
  - "Russian Eighteenth-Century Literature Through Party-Colored Spectacles", The Slavic and East European Journal, Vol. XV, No. 1, Spring, 1957, printed copy (Folder 9)
  - Review of M. Karpovich and D. Chizhevskii, eds., Russkii Literaturnyii Arkhiv, Novyi Zhurnal, Bk. XLVIII, March 1957, printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "Soviet Literature After De-Stalinization", Bulletin of the Institute for the Study of the U.S.S.R., May 1957, printed copy (Folder 11)
  - "Russkii narod-glavnyi soiuznik v bor'be s kommunizmom", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, June 7, 1957, typescript draft and printed copy. Relates to article by Iosef Mackiewicz in Wiadomoczi, May 19, 1957 (Folder 12)
  - Book reviews, 1958, printed copies (Folder 13)
  - "Sovetskoe literaturovedenie v 1957 godu", Vestnik Instituta po izucheniiu SSSR, 1958, printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Dead Souls and Living Reputations", Soviet Survey, Jan.-March 1958, reprint (Folder 15)
  - "Der Fall Dudinzew", Rhein-Neckar Zeitung, Feb. 15-16, 1958, printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "Novyi sovetskii zhurnal", Novoye Russkoe Slovo, Feb. 16, 1958, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1956-1959 (Folder 17)
  - "Russia 5 Years After Stalin: Literature", The New Leader, April 7, 1958, printed copy and (Folder 18)
  - "Van nghe so viet. Nam nam sau Xit-Ta-Lin", Huong Xa, No. 17, 1958, Vietnamese translation of above, printed copy
  - Review of Vladimir Smolenskii, Sobranie Stikhotvorenii, Novyi Zhurnal, Bk. LIII, June 1958, printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "Report on Renato Poggioli's The Poets of Russia", Aug. 7, 1958, typescript draft (Folder 20)
  - "Russian Writers in Exile: Problems of an Emigre Literature", Comparative Literature, Vol. II. Lecture delivered at the Second Congress of the International Comparative Literature Association at the University of North Carolina, Sept. 8-12, 1958, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 21)
  - Book reviews, 1959, printed copies (Folder 22)
  - Letters to the editor and obituary, 1959, printed copies (Folder 23)
  - "Sovetskoe literaturovedenie v 1958 g.", printed copy (Folder 24)
  - "Russian Writers in Exile: Problems of an Emigre Literature", Institute of International Studies University of California, 1959, printed copy "Sovetskoe literaturovedenie v 1958 g.", Vestnik po izucheniiu SSSR, No. 3, 1959, printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Soviet Literature Before 1930", review of Viacheslav Zavalishin, Early Soviet Writers, The New Leader, Jan. 19, 1959, printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "O Vsevolode Rozhdestvenskom, Osipe Mandel'shtame i drugikh", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, March 8, 1959, printed copy (Folder 27)
  - "O stat'e N. Ul'ianova", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, March 31, 1959, printed copy. Also see scrapbook, 1950-1959 (Folder 28)
  - "O literaturnykh nravakh-tam i tut", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, June 7, 1959, printed copy (Folder 29)
  - "Die sowjetische Literaturwissenschaft in jungster Zeit", Sowjet-Studien, July, 1959, printed copy (Folder 30)
  - "Kak vret Aleksei Adzhubei", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Sept. 14, 1959 (Folder 31)
  - Book reviews, 1960 (Folder 32)
  - Letters to editor, 1960 (Folder 33)
  - "K istorii biblioteki P.N. Miliukova v Kalifornii", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Feb. 21, 1960, printed copy (Folder 34)
  - Book reviews, 1961, printed copies (Folder 35)
  - California Slavic Studies, reviews, 1961-1979 (Folder 36)
  - Russian Stories: Russkie rasskazy, 1961
    - Correspondence, Bantam Books, 1960-1962 (Folder 37)
    - Review, The Slavic and East European Journal, printed copy, 1962 (Folder 38)
  - "Podpol'naia sovetskaia poeziia", Russkaia Mysl', May 25, 1961, printed copy (Folder 39)
  - "Poeziia pod spudom", Russkaia Mysl', July 13, 1961, printed copy (Folder 40)
  - "Pamiati M. M. Shneerova", obituary, Russkaia Mysl', July 29, 1961, printed copy (Folder 41)
  - Entries, Chambers' Encyclopedia, galley proofs, Oct. 19, 1961 (Folder 42)
  - "Podpol'naia sovetskaia komediia", Russkaia Mysl', June 10-Nov. 30, 1961, printed copies (Folder 43)
  - Lexikon der Weltliteratur im 20 Jahrhundert, Friedrich Hansen-Love ed., Verlag Herder Freiburg, 1962
    - Correspondence between Gleb Struve and Forschungsinstitut fur Europaische Gegenwartskunde and Verlag Herder Freiburg, 1955-1969 (Box 64, Folder 1-2)
    - Typescript drafts of biographies submitted by Gleb Struve, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous material sent to Gleb Struve by publisher, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Review of Literatur Lexikon in Osteuropa, Feb.-March, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Book reviews, 1962, printed copies (Folder 6)
  - Letters to the editor, 1962, printed copies (Folder 7)
  - N. Gumilev, sobranie sochinenii, reviews, 1962-1963, typescript and printed copies (Folder 8)
  - "Russkii turist v Parizhe v 1839 godu", Russkaia Mysl', Jan. 16, 1962, printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "O 'poluzapretnoi' literature", Russkaia Mysl', March 31, 1962, printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "The Transition From Russian to Soviet Literature", paper delivered at Conference on Soviet Literature, Oxford, July 1962 (Folder 11)
  - "The Aesthetic Function in Russian Literature", Slavic Review, Sept. 1962, printed copy (Folder 12)
  - "O Konstantine Simonove i 'zlodeianiiakh' Stalina", Russkaia Mysl', Dec. 13, 1962, printed copy (Folder 13)
  - Book reviews, 1963, printed copies (Folder 14)
  - "Ob odnom stikhotvorenii S. Solovieva", Mosty, No. 10, 1963, printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "On Some Malpractices in Soviet Literary Scholarship", The Slavic and East European Journal, Vol. VII, No.2, 1963, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 16)
  - "O Vladislave Bronevskom", Russkaia Mysl', Jan. 10, 1963, printed copy (Folder 17)
  - "The 'Coffee Break' and After, Some Reflections on the Soviet Literary Scene", New Rebublic, Feb. 1963, typescript copy (Folder 18)
  - "After the Coffee Break", The New Republic, Feb. 2, 1963, printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "Do novoi ottepeli daleko", Russkaia Mysl', Feb. 2, 1963, printed copy (Folder 20)
  - "Sovetskie anekdoty i chastushki", Russkaia Mysl', May 7, 1963, printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Nakanune ideologicheskogo plenuma", Russkaia Mysl', May 18, 1963, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 22)
  - "'Slovo o polku Igoreve'--ne pamiatnik XII veka?", Russkaia Mysl', June 1, 1963, printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "Eshche o 'Slove o polku Igoreve'", Russkaia Mysl', July 2, 1963, printed copy (Folder 24)
  - Book reviews, 1964, printed copies (Folder 25)
  - Letters to the editor, 1964, printed copies (Folder 26)
  - "Western Writing on Soviet Literature", Institute of International Studies, Slavic and East European Series, Reprint No. 121, Jan. 1964, printed copy (Folder 27)
  - Letters to the editor, 1965, printed copies (Folder 28)
  - Utloe zhil'e: Izbranye stikhi 1915-1949, 1965 and second edition, 1978
    - Typescript drafts (Folder 29)
    - Reviews, 1966-1971, typescript and printed copies (Folder 30)
  - "Neizdannoe pis'mo i shutochnye stikhi K. I. Chukovskogo", Mosty, 1965, printed copy (Folder 31)
  - "O novoi sovetskoi literaturnoi entsiklopedii", Russkaia Mysl', Sept. 28, 1965, printed copy (Folder 32)
  - Book reviews, 1966, printed copies (Folder 33)
  - Letters to the editor, 1966, printed copies (Folder 34)
  - Entries on Valentin Kataev, Aleksandr Kuprin, Dmitri Merezhkovski, Dmitri Pisemskii, Encyclopedia Britannica, tearsheets, 1966 (Folder 35)
  - "Maksim Gor'kii o Lenine, lenintsakh i sovetskoi vlasti v 1917-1918 g.g.", Russkaia Mysl', 1966, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 36)
  - "K delu Siniavskogo i Daniela", Russkaia Mysl', March 12, 1966, printed copy (Folder 37)
  - "Samoprigvozhdenie k pozornomu stolbu", Russkaia Mysl', June 4, 1966, printed copy (Folder 38)
  - "Pamiati V. N. Korvin-Piotrovskogo", Russkaia Mysl', June 11, 1966, printed copy (Folder 39)
  - "49 let tomu nazad", Russkaia Mysl', Nov. 8, 1966, printed copy (Folder 40)
  - "Dva stikhotvoreniia iz Rossii", Russkaia Mysl', Nov. 29, 1966, printed copy (Folder 41)
  - Letters to the editor, 1967 (Folder 42)
  - A Century of Russian Prose and Verse, 1967, correspondence, Harcourt, Brace and World, 1964-1967 (Folder 43)
  - "Russian Writers in Exile: Problems of an Emigre Literature", Comparative Literature, Proceedings of the ICLA Congress (ed. W.P. Friederich), 1959, printed copy (Folder 44)
  - "Slushaia Evtushenko", Russkaia Mysl', Jan. 24, 1967, printed copy (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - "Ob Anatolii Tarasenkove i o sovetskoi kritike voobshche", Russkaia Mysl', April 13, 1967, printed copy (Folder 2)
  - "Pamiati N. A. Eleneva", Russkaia Mysl', May 9, 1967, printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "O chetvertom tome 'Kratkoi sovetskoi entsiklopedii'", Russkaia Mysl', Aug. 3, 10, 1967, typescript draft and printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "L'Acmeisme russe dans le cadre de la rennaissance neo-classique en Europe", paper delivered at the Fifth Congress of the Inernational Comparative Literature Association, Belgrade, Aug.-Sept. 1967
    - Miscellaneous notes by Gleb Struve (Folder 5)
    - Boisson, Alain, Rapport sur le Dictionnaire International des Termes Litteraires, Belgrade, Yugoslavia, 1967 (Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous material on conference. Includes circulars and schedules, typescript and printed matter, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - "V. A. Lednitskii (1891-1967)", Russkaia Mysl', Nov. 26, 1967, printed copy (Folder 8)
  - Book reviews, 1968, printed copies (Folder 9)
  - Letters to the editor, 1968, printed copies (Folder 10)
  - "Iz istorii russkoi zarubezhnoi literatury. Perepiska N. A. Bunina i P. B. Struve (1920-1941)", Zapiski Russkoi Akademicheskoi Gruppy, Vol II, 1968, galley proof (Folder 11)
  - "Iz moeii perepiski s pisateliami. Pis'ma G. V. Ivanova, M. I. Tsvetaevoi i M. A. Aldanova", Mosty, No. 13-14, printed copy (Folder 12)
  - Book reviews, 1969, printed copies (Folder 13)
  - Letters to the editor, 1969, printed copies (Folder 14)
  - Polemic between Gleb Struve and Arkadii Borman in Novoye Russkoe Slovo related to P. B. Struve, 1969-1971, printed copies (Folder 15)
  - "K stoletiiu so dnia rozhdeniia P. B. Struve", Zapiski Russkoi Akademicheskoi Gruppy v S.Sh.A., vol. III, 1969, tearsheets (Folder 16)
  - "Russian Literature", entry on Russian literature in Collier's Encyclopedia, tearsheets, 1968 (Folder 17)
  - "Boris Polevoi ob 'osvobozhdenii' Pragi", Russkaia Mysl', Jan. 16, 1969, printed copy (Folder 18)
  - "I. G. Ivanov, V. Khodasevich i A. Kondratiev--zapozdalye utochneniia", Russkaia Mysl', Jan. 30, 1969, printed copy (Folder 19)
  - "O piatom tome 'KLE'", Russkaia Mysl', April 17-May 1, 1969, printed copies (Folder 20)
  - "Cheshskii slovar' russkikh pisatelei", Russkaia Mysl', Sept. 18, 1969, printed copy (Folder 21)
  - Letters to the editor, 1970, printed copies and drafts (Folder 22)
  - "Iz moego arkhiva", Mosty, No. 15, 1970, printed copy (Folder 23)
  - "K piatidesiatiletiiu okonchaniia grazhdanskoi voiny na Iuge Rossii. Neizdannye dokumenty iz arkhivov P. B. Struve", Mosty No. 15, printed copy (Folder 24)
  - "P. B. Struve o Lenine", Russkaia Mysl', April 23, 1970, printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Stikhi A. Tarkovskogo o M. Tsvetaevoi i O. Mandel'shtame", Russkaia Mysl', June 11, 1970, printed copy (Folder 26)
  - "Iz dalekogo proshlogo; P. B. Struve i V. A. Maklakov na skam'e podsudimykh v sviazi s delom Beilisa", Russkaia Mysl', July 2, 1970, printed copy (Folder 27)